<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<feed xml:lang="en-US" xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xmlns:opensearch="http://a9.com/-/spec/opensearch/1.1/" xmlns:s="http://jadedpixel.com/-/spec/shopify">
  <id>https://www.tucsonbeads.com/blogs/news.atom</id>
  <link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="https://www.tucsonbeads.com/blogs/news"/>
  <link rel="self" type="application/atom+xml" href="https://www.tucsonbeads.com/blogs/news.atom"/>
  <title>Tucson Beads - News</title>
  <updated>2020-12-25T08:00:00-05:00</updated>
  <author>
    <name>Tucson Beads</name>
  </author>
  <entry>
    <id>https://www.tucsonbeads.com/blogs/news/buying-guide-things-to-consider-while-buying-loose-gemstones-in-wholesale</id>
    <published>2020-12-25T08:00:00-05:00</published>
    <updated>2020-12-26T06:21:13-05:00</updated>
    <link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="https://www.tucsonbeads.com/blogs/news/buying-guide-things-to-consider-while-buying-loose-gemstones-in-wholesale"/>
    <title>Buying Guide: Things to consider while buying loose gemstones in wholesale</title>
    <author>
      <name>Catherine Phillips</name>
    </author>
    <content type="html">
      <![CDATA[<p>A first-time purchaser in the wholesale market, that too for loose gemstones? Don't know who to trust, where to buy, how, and for how much? Luckily enough, we have a list of the dos’ and don'ts for you right here, so read on!</p>
<p>Let us first quickly go through the <strong>pro tips</strong>!</p>
<ul>
<li>Colour and lighting go hand in hand since the color of some gemstones changes with the change in the wavelength of the light present. Do not be fooled by dealers using full-spectrum lighting to bring out the brilliance of the stones. You might end up buying something completely different than intended.</li>
<li>The certificate of guarantee of the stones is of utmost importance, especially if you don’t have personal relations with the dealer. Countries have their standard authorities that certify these gems. In India's case, it is the Laboratories of the Gemological Institute od America (<span><a href="https://www.gia.edu/">GIA</a></span>). A government certificate proves that the stones’ quality standards comply with the laboratory standards.</li>
<li>The quality, size, history, and authenticity of a gem are important and shouldn't be overlooked or taken lightly. Other details such as the cutting and clarity should be checked too.</li>
<li>In the case of online purchases, wholesale buyers should exercise special precautions since photos may be easily manipulated.</li>
<li>A lot of synthetic and imitation gemstones are present in the market and are cheaper than the natural ones. Always do your research about what you’re looking for and where you can get the best price and quality for it.</li>
<li>Keep a good margin for the mark up in case the purchase has been made for commercial purposes. The value of a gemstone rises multifold depending on the re-cutting, polishing, etc.</li>
<li>Even naturally occurring stones have flaws and imperfections. Gemologists often use them to identify the origin of the stone. The best quality gemstones have deep tones, saturation, and are of natural, brilliant colors.</li>
<li>To identify fakes, use magnifiers to check for air bubbles, scratches, color concentrations, and atypical opacity.</li>
<li>Try to buy as low as possible but buy right. If the prices are unusually low, you have a right to be suspicious. Moreover, the prices aren’t very predictable in this industry.</li>
</ul>
<p>A dealer may belong to any of <span><a href="https://www.gemsociety.org/article/inner-workings-gem-trade/">the five tiers</a></span>, and fundamental knowledge of this tier system may prove to be beneficial.</p>
<p><span> </span></p>
<p>Always remember your <strong>four C’s:</strong></p>
<ul>
<li>
<strong>Carat </strong>– is determined by the weight or density of the gemstone. One carat contains 100 points, but that does not mean that two species of stones, both worth one carat each, will be of the same size. It is so because stones have varying densities and hence may physically vary in size.</li>
<li>
<strong>Cut </strong>- refers to the aspects or facets that the gemstone is cut into. It enhances the depth, light-reflecting property, and general brilliance of the stone. Do not confuse it with the shape of the stones.</li>
<li>
<strong>Clarity</strong> - refers to the number of flaws a gem has. The lesser the flaws, the better the stone's clarity and quality, the higher the price. In a few cases, it may be seen with the naked eye, but usually, a magnifier is necessary to check for clarity.</li>
<li>
<strong>Colour </strong>­­– much like the animals you love, gems have species too. These species have different colors, for instance, Emerald is green, and Sapphire is blue. Nowadays, it is common for dealers to carry gems that have undergone extensive treatments to enhance the stones' color.</li>
</ul>
<p><strong> </strong></p>
<p><strong> </strong></p>
<p><strong> </strong></p>
<p><strong>The basics of gemstone trading</strong></p>
<p>The United States has some of the most beautiful stones, occurring naturally and locally available too! To name a few, there are Opal, Sapphire, Jasper, Tourmaline and many more! The eastern countries price their stones at a much lower rates and hence, a lot of Americans purchase theirs abroad. For more data, click <span><a href="https://geology.com/gemstones/">here</a></span>.</p>
<p>The rarer the stone, the higher the value. It is a good idea to shop for gemstones at clearance sales or hoard during 'off-season.' In case you are dealing with e-retailers, make sure to read the fine print, the description, and T&amp;C and get the guarantee certificate of your precious and semi-precious stones. Also, know their return policy, if there, as well as shipping information. Since you're buying in bulk, negotiate, and bargain well.</p>
<p>You might want to visit trade fairs or monthly gemstone markets if you have the option. Purchases at brick and mortar stores are always preferable for inspection and reliance purposes. For instance, the color is as important as the cut, size, weight, polishing, inclusions, brilliance, and finishing of the stones, but these are hard to identify in online purchases. Examining the gemstones might prove to be a tedious process but is equally important too. You should always know what you’re in for.</p>]]>
    </content>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>https://www.tucsonbeads.com/blogs/news/the-checklist-you-must-have-before-purchasing-pave-diamond-pendant</id>
    <published>2020-12-21T08:00:00-05:00</published>
    <updated>2020-12-27T02:29:14-05:00</updated>
    <link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="https://www.tucsonbeads.com/blogs/news/the-checklist-you-must-have-before-purchasing-pave-diamond-pendant"/>
    <title>The checklist you must have before purchasing Pave Diamond Pendant</title>
    <author>
      <name>Catherine Phillips</name>
    </author>
    <content type="html">
      <![CDATA[<p>A beautiful pave diamond pendant positioned perfectly around the neck is usually brought for its appearance. It is the most popular naturally occurring stone, and the ones who own some know why!  It is no surprise that not everyone can afford one, and the ones who do want to make it worth their while and money.</p>
<p>It is a well-known fact that diamonds are expensive and drain months’ worth of salary at a go. In the world of internet and connectivity, it sometimes becomes difficult to optimize search due to 'too much information.' Hence, it becomes important that you know exactly what you're spending your months of sweat and blood over and how to go about it. Without any confusion and without any wastage of money, you should make an informed decision. To make such a decision, a checklist will always come in handy.</p>
<p>You should make sure that the following points have been covered in that checklist:</p>
<ul>
<li>The pendant should’ve been made from diamonds certified by a reputable national or international laboratory such as <span><a href="https://www.gia.edu/">GIA</a></span> or <span><a href="https://www.igi.org/">IGI</a></span>.</li>
<li>Making the purchase from a reputable vendor, an entity you’ll be able to hold accountable in the future if required. Said vendor should preferably be experienced and knowledgeable in their field.</li>
<li>As important as the appearance is, the Carat precedes it in terms of price determination. It refers to the weight of the diamond, and different species vary in density; hence, carat weight and market value.</li>
<li>The <span><a href="https://www.gemsociety.org/article/a-consumers-guide-to-gem-grading/">four C’s</a></span>, i.e., Cut, Clarity, Carat, and Colour, are your best friends. They all have grading scales, so don't shy away from asking questions about it all from your jeweler. Amongst these, <em>the cut</em> of the diamonds used is paramount.</li>
<li>The diamonds used should have a high level of fire and brilliance, i.e., sparkle. They should be finely cut for it to reflect maximum light back to the viewer.</li>
<li>Examine the diamonds closely for any inclusions and blemishes. The clarity of such diamonds in pendants is more important than in any other jewelry.</li>
<li>Naturally occurring diamonds aren’t completely flawless, contrary to popular belief. Good quality ones are, however, ‘<em>eye clean</em>.'</li>
<li>In pave diamond pendants, there are a number of diamonds. These have a <em>table</em> each- the flat portion on the top of these diamonds. The ideal size of these is 53- 59%. If you realize that the diamonds are not reflecting the light back to you, the faulty table size could be the reason.</li>
<li>Another reason for this light escaping rather than giving a sparkly effect could be that the depth % isn’t ideal. Depth % is the ratio of depth to width. An ideal depth % are regarded as 59- 63%. Otherwise, the diamonds will again perform poorly and completely beat the purpose of purchase.</li>
<li>You probably never took the pendant setting very seriously but from now on, make sure to do that. The prong setting has become famous as it allows maximum light to enter, giving a sparkling effect to the diamond.</li>
<li>How often and on what occasion you use your purchase will determine the size of the diamond pendant.</li>
<li>While polish and symmetry have little to do with the performance of the diamond pendant, you might still want to look out as they affect the overall appearance.</li>
<li>There are six popular types of pave setting in the States- Micro, U-Cut, French, Petite, Bright Cut and the Scalloped pave.</li>
<li>The chain and clasp to go along are important too. The cable chain is the most popular choice. The length of the chain has an impact on the overall appearance of the exquisite piece, so choose the one that suits you the best!</li>
</ul>
<p>Pave diamonds are said to accentuate the entire piece and show an extra level of detail. Pendant settings are also important considerations that may be customized as per preferences. For shape and style choices, consider the likes of the giftee.</p>
<p><strong>Bonus tip:</strong> Some say that you can’t go wrong with the classic round shape!</p>
In the world of the internet and global connectivity, it sometimes becomes difficult to optimize search due to 'too much information.' Hence, it becomes important that you know exactly what you’re spending your months of sweat and blood over and how to go about it. Without any confusion and without any wastage of money, you should be able to make an informed decision (hopefully with the help of the above-mentioned points). Some of the best places to have the most convenient shopping experience of <a href="https://www.tucsonbeads.com/collections/pave-diamond-charms">pave diamond pendants wholesale</a> would be <a href="https://newyorkgemco.com/" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer">Newyork Gem Co</a>! It provide an almost real shopping experience of <a href="https://www.tucsonbeads.com/collections/pave-diamond-charms">wholesale pave diamond pendants</a> online too! <em>Happy Shopping!</em>]]>
    </content>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>https://www.tucsonbeads.com/blogs/news/what-gemstone-beads-symbolize</id>
    <published>2020-09-30T09:00:00-04:00</published>
    <updated>2020-11-26T06:42:18-05:00</updated>
    <link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="https://www.tucsonbeads.com/blogs/news/what-gemstone-beads-symbolize"/>
    <title>What Gemstone Beads Symbolize?</title>
    <author>
      <name>Catherine Phillips</name>
    </author>
    <content type="html">
      <![CDATA[<p>There are many <a href="https://www.tucsonbeads.com/collections/gemstones" title="gemstone beads for jewelry making">Gemstones</a> and every gemstone have their own meanings and symbolize something. People relate stones with human emotions, positivity, luck, healing properties, spiritual beliefs, etc. Let us understand the real meanings of some of these <a href="https://www.tucsonbeads.com/collections/precious-beads" title="precious beads wholesale">gemstones beads</a>.</p>
<ol>
<li>Agate</li>
</ol>
<p>This Gemstone bead helps to feel you stable in your life. After using this gemstone for a long time, you start feeling happy with your life. Basically, this stone helps you to provide eternal happiness. It helps you to feel grounded and self-sufficient from inside. All of them have their own properties but all are related to metaphysical work.</p>
<ol start="2">
<li>Bloodstone</li>
</ol>
<p>Bloodstone gemstone beads is another gemstone that helps you to keep grounded. If you feel that you are losing your path and not very focused, then this gemstone will help you. It is one of the varieties of Jasper which is forest green in color, quite reddish too. Its yellow color is a rare one.</p>
<ol start="3">
<li>Magnesite</li>
</ol>
<p>This gemstone is very helpful for those who are less conscious and want to become more conscious. Magnesite helps to increase inner consciousness. This stone has a very good effect on the awakening of the third eye that helps you to increase your spirituality.</p>
<ol start="4">
<li>Selenite</li>
</ol>
<p>Selenite is a symbol of purity and if you are feeling negative and finding your surroundings negative then you must purchase a Selenite Gemstone.  You can carry it as a gemstone bead jewelry. Keep this Selenite close to your body for its best effect. But due to its softness, it is quite hard to convert it in jewelry or the process becomes very expensive. Generally, it is used with any other gemstone and whenever you use it with other gemstones then it also enhances its properties.</p>
<ol start="5">
<li>Spinel</li>
</ol>
<p>Spinel is another very effective gemstone that gives you hope, helps you to realize that you are alive, the joy of living, etc. This stone is available in many colors which signifies that it can help you with many chakras. Spinel helps you to get some freshness in life. If you are someone suffering from bad relationships and emotionally broken then you should use Spinel gemstone. If you get some life-ending or suicidal thoughts then this is a real gem for you.</p>
<ol start="6">
<li>Sodalite</li>
</ol>
<p>Sodalite helps in providing better observation and also gives you some power to understand the future. It helps you to gain psychic powers that helps you to understand someone's future. Sodalite Gemstone is one of the popular stones used by astrologers which ease them to tell your future.</p>
<ol start="7">
<li>Unacoit</li>
</ol>
<p>Unacoit helps to keep you fit physically. It helps you to get rid of your bad habits such as overeating, anger, overweight, etc.. If you are suffering from problems related to your body then Unacoit gemstone will help you a lot. It will help you to keep your anger in control.</p>
<p>These are some of the gemstones with their meanings. These gemstones are the symbol of different <a href="https://www.tucsonbeads.com/collections/healing-stones" title="healing crystals jewelry">healing</a> powers. You should use gemstone as per your needs. You can use <a href="https://www.tucsonbeads.com/collections" title="gemstone beads">gemstone beads</a> in jewelry to keep it close to your body.</p>]]>
    </content>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>https://www.tucsonbeads.com/blogs/news/what-are-semi-precious-gemstones-beads</id>
    <published>2020-09-20T09:00:00-04:00</published>
    <updated>2020-11-26T06:48:28-05:00</updated>
    <link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="https://www.tucsonbeads.com/blogs/news/what-are-semi-precious-gemstones-beads"/>
    <title>What are Semi-precious Gemstones Beads</title>
    <author>
      <name>Catherine Phillips</name>
    </author>
    <content type="html">
      <![CDATA[<p><strong>Introduction of Semi-precious beads</strong></p>
<p>Semi-precious beads are the beads that are made up of pieces of mineral that are obtained naturally. Their commercial value is low as compared to the rare and costly gemstones such as Diamond, Ruby, Emeralds, etc. Semi-precious beads are less rare as compared to a diamond-like Gemstone and that’s why they are considerably low at price. They are used as jewelry ornaments on a general basis. These beads look beautiful and some of them are used as healing crystals. Generally, all of them are made up of natural minerals but there are some exceptions that are not natural minerals. Such exceptions include Jet, Pearl, Coral, Amber which are obtained from fossilized tree resins.</p>
<p><strong>Types of Semi-precious beads</strong></p>
<p>There are many Semi-precious beads that are used as an ornament in jewelry. These are shiny crystals and people love to wear them. Let me introduce some of them to you.</p>
<ol>
<li>
<strong> </strong><strong>Garnet</strong>
</li>
</ol>
<p>Garnet is one of the popular semi-precious stones as very much resembles the precious stone, Ruby. People who love ruby but cannot afford it as it is very costly then they buy Garnet. It has a deep red color and that makes it similar to Ruby. As it is red in color people usually look at it as a symbol of love and highly use it for engagement rings.</p>
<ol start="2">
<li>
<strong> </strong><strong>Amethyst</strong>
</li>
</ol>
<p>Amethyst is a semi-precious stone that is of violet color and a symbol of spirituality. People who are in search of peace love to keep it with them. Another reason for loving this is their durability. This stone is highly durable and once was used by kings and queens similar to Diamonds.</p>
<ol start="3">
<li>
<strong> </strong><strong>Onyx</strong>
</li>
</ol>
<p>Onyx is another popular semi precious beads that are black in color. This color looks really classy and people love to carry this classy black onyx stone in their jewelry. This kept on attracting people and that’s why it is also known for its magical properties. There is no scientific claim about its magics but some people believe in it.</p>
<ol start="4">
<li>
<strong> </strong><strong>Opal</strong>
</li>
</ol>
<p>Opal is a unique crystal with an amazing property of reflecting light and after that, it changes its color. When someone wears this stone, it shows rainbow-like colors as it reflects the light. This helps to enhance the jewelry and its design. Opal has also another variant which is quite rare and it is in black color. This Opal bead is quite costly as compared to its general variant.</p>
<p> </p>
<p>These are some of the amazing Semi-precious beads that are less costly as compared to precious Gemstones but high in demand.</p>]]>
    </content>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>https://www.tucsonbeads.com/blogs/news/what-are-healing-crystals</id>
    <published>2020-09-17T09:00:00-04:00</published>
    <updated>2020-11-26T06:43:06-05:00</updated>
    <link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="https://www.tucsonbeads.com/blogs/news/what-are-healing-crystals"/>
    <title>What are Healing Crystals ?</title>
    <author>
      <name>Catherine Phillips</name>
    </author>
    <content type="html">
      <![CDATA[<p><strong>Introduction to Healing Stones and Crystals</strong></p>
<p><a href="https://www.tucsonbeads.com/collections/healing-stones" title="healing stones and crystals">Healing stones</a> and crystals are a number of different types of crystals that have the ability to heal the mind, soul, and body. These crystals are known for the huge exchange of energy. They provide positive energy to your soul and mind while help in getting rid of negative energies. While anyone places such healing stones on any part of the body, negative energies came out of the body. This method is treated as therapy but there is no scientific claim over it. There are many types of healing stones each with different structures, shapes, and have a different meaning. Different people choose different healing stones and crystals according to their problems and needs. Each and every healing stone have their own meaning and work differently for everyone.</p>
<p><strong>Different Types of Healing Crystals</strong></p>
<p>There are many different types of <a href="https://www.tucsonbeads.com/collections/healing-stones" title="healing stone beads">healing crystals</a>. Let us discuss some of them below.</p>
<ol>
<li>
<strong> </strong><strong><span>Clear Quartz</span></strong>
</li>
</ol>
<p><span>Clear Quartz is considered as a  master healer and it is white in color. This white crystal absorbs, store, release, and regulate energy to amplify it. Generally, clear crystals like clear quartz help to stimulate the immune system and provides power to balance your entire body. This stone is paired with other healing stones and crystals to enhance its power and abilities. If you are someone who is looking for a crystal to help their immune system then you should choose this clear quartz white crystal and for more benefits pair it with another healing stone. </span></p>
<ol start="2">
<li>
<strong> </strong><strong><span>Rose Quartz</span></strong>
</li>
</ol>
<p><span>As we all know Rose is a symbol for love, whether it is Valentine or Wedding Anniversary, we always choose a Rose to show our love to our partner. Similarly, Rose Quartz stone is all about love and relationships. If you are someone facing any disputes in your close relationships then you should definitely choose this crystal. This will help you to restore your trust and harmony in any relationship whether it is close or not.</span></p>
<ol start="3">
<li>
<strong> </strong><strong><span>Citrine</span></strong>
</li>
</ol>
<p><span>Citrine crystal is another healing crystal that heals your negative traits such as fear, anger. This stone helps you to get joy, enthusiasm, and happiness in life. So if you are someone who is suffering from negative thought and not feeling positive then you should use this crystal. This helps you to provide motivation for life and helps you to gain peace. </span></p>
<ol start="4">
<li>
<strong> </strong><strong><span>Obsidian</span></strong>
</li>
</ol>
<p><span>Obsidian is a kind of crystal that acts as a shield for your physical negativities. It also helps you to get your true sense of self by removing your emotional blockage. It may help you to reduce pain and cramps. So if you are someone who is suffering from physical problems then you should choose this obsidian stone. </span></p>
<ol start="5">
<li>
<strong> </strong><strong><span>Sapphire</span></strong>
</li>
</ol>
<p><span>Sapphire is a blue colored stone that helps you get wisdom and Royalty. If you are looking for success and money then you should go for this royal sapphire stone. This is a symbol of royal people as it attracts prosperity and wealth and helps to gain money. </span></p>
<ol start="6">
<li>
<strong> </strong><strong><span>Amethyst</span></strong>
</li>
</ol>
<p><span>Amethyst is a purple color crystal that is popularly used as a thought purifier.  People who get bad dreams while sleeping also use this stone as it helps to get rid of bad dreams. </span></p>
<ol start="7">
<li>
<strong> </strong><strong><span>Tiger’s eye</span></strong>
</li>
</ol>
<p><span>Tiger’s eye crystal is used as a motivational element. Whenever someone feels demotivated towards anything this stone helps to get motivation. This stone keeps boosting your motivation. </span></p>
<ol start="8">
<li>
<strong> </strong><strong><span>Tourmaline</span></strong>
</li>
</ol>
<p><span>Tourmaline is a crystal that is known for providing alertness by relieving stress and it increases mental health and blood circulation. </span></p>
<ol start="9">
<li>
<strong> </strong><strong><span>Sunstone</span></strong>
</li>
</ol>
<p><span>As the name suggests, it helps to provide you energies. It can brighten your future by providing positivity. It increases originality and helps to gain independence.  You become more confident and can take your decisions wisely.</span></p>
<p> </p>
<p><span>These are some of the known healing stones and crystals. You can choose healing stones according to your requirements and problems. You can use more than one stone or pairing of stones for more positivity and a better life.</span></p>]]>
    </content>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>https://www.tucsonbeads.com/blogs/news/reasons-why-you-should-buy-loose-gemstones</id>
    <published>2020-09-02T09:00:00-04:00</published>
    <updated>2020-11-26T07:32:30-05:00</updated>
    <link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="https://www.tucsonbeads.com/blogs/news/reasons-why-you-should-buy-loose-gemstones"/>
    <title>Reasons Why You Should Buy Loose Gemstones?</title>
    <author>
      <name>Catherine Phillips</name>
    </author>
    <content type="html">
      <![CDATA[<p>Gemstones have been used for astrological purposes as well as to enhance the look of the jewelry. There are a variety of <a href="https://www.tucsonbeads.com/collections/gemstones" target="_blank" title="gemstones" rel="noopener noreferrer">gemstones</a> available in the market like ruby, emerald, garnet, sapphire, topaz, blue topaz, pyrope garnet, tanzanite, opal, aquamarine, and many more.</p>
<div style="float: left;">
<br><br>
</div>
<p>But you won’t always find jewelry embedded with your favorite gemstone since all the gemstones aren’t available in considerable quantity, and retail jewelry stores don’t have it due to the short supply. However, not opting to buy gemstone jewelry from a retail store because of the lack of variety isn’t only the reason you should opt for customized jewelry. Another reason is that the low-quality gemstones are used to make expensive jewelry. Once the gemstone is embedded in the metal, it is very difficult to judge the quality of the stone. Retailers are not concerned about the quality of the gemstone used; they just focus on the jewelry. The reason for using low-quality stones in making jewelry is that it is impossible to source high-quality stones in bulk.</p>
<p>If you want to buy <a href="https://www.tucsonbeads.com/collections/loose-gemstones" target="_blank" title="Loose Gemstones for sale" rel="noopener noreferrer">loose gemstones</a> for yourself either to make custom jewelry or something related to the astrological purpose, you should buy from a specialized gemstone dealer. <a href="https://www.tucsonbeads.com/" target="_blank" title="Wholesale Beads and Loose Gemstones Suppliers" rel="noopener noreferrer">Gemstones dealers</a> deal in loose gemstone for sale, wherein you can choose the color, cut, and size of the gemstone. Wholesale loose gemstones dealers and high-end gemstone dealers give certificates from recognized gemological laboratories for gemstones.</p>
<p>If you want to buy gemstones, then it is better you buy loose gemstones since the quality, and the color of the stones embedded in the jewelry can’t be identified. Expensive gemstones should always be evaluated loose, and even laboratories prefer to test loose gemstones.</p>
<p> Let’s check out the reasons to buy wholesale loose gemstones!</p>
<ul>
<li>You have the liberty to choose your favorite gemstone.</li>
<li>You can be assured of the color and quality of the stone.</li>
<li>You can get it lab tested easily.</li>
<li>You can get your jewelry customized.</li>
<li>You can get a good deal buying wholesale loose gemstones.</li>
</ul>
In the end, buying loose gemstones and making customized jewelry it will not only ensure the quality of the stone embedded in the jewelry but also you can choose which stone you want to in the jewelry.]]>
    </content>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>https://www.tucsonbeads.com/blogs/news/15859703-first-post</id>
    <published>2020-07-15T09:00:00-04:00</published>
    <updated>2020-11-26T07:32:59-05:00</updated>
    <link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="https://www.tucsonbeads.com/blogs/news/15859703-first-post"/>
    <title>Everything you need to know about Pave Diamond Engagement Rings!</title>
    <author>
      <name>Catherine Phillips</name>
    </author>
    <summary type="html">
      <![CDATA[<span>Is your engagement around the corner? Or All set to propose your loved one?</span><p><a class="read-more" href="https://www.tucsonbeads.com/blogs/news/15859703-first-post">More</a></p>]]>
    </summary>
    <content type="html">
      <![CDATA[<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">Is your engagement around the corner? Or All set to propose your loved one?</span></p>
<br>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">Whatever might be the reason a stunning looking ring will say it all. Pave diamond engagement rings are one such type of ring that is glamorous and elegant, with diamonds embedded across the band. </span></p>
<br>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">What is a Pave diamond engagement ring?</span></p>
<br>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">Pave is derived from a French word "to pave," the paving is a setting wherein the small diamonds are placed with minimal gap between them, creating a beautiful appearance of the unbroken diamond surface. This setting enhances the appearance of the centerpiece.</span></p>
<br>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">Pave settings rings look stunning and are available in various styles and designs from vintage to contemporary. If you are looking for a marvelous engagement ring, then you should opt for a Pave diamond engagement ring.</span></p>
<br>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">Pave settings rings are one of the most sought-after designs for engagement rings and wedding rings. There are various paves you can choose from, so here a quick run through the types of pave settings styles.</span></p>
<br>
<p><b>Micro Pave</b></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">In micro pave settings, diamonds are usually smaller than 0.01 carat and are placed around the band, giving a look that the band is made of diamond. The diamonds are placed in several rows, and a standard micro pave setting engagement ring has a minimum of 50 diamonds. It is one of the most beautiful rings with detailed work. These types of rings are delicate and difficult to clean.</span></p>
<br>
<p><b>French Pave</b></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">French Pave, also known as fishtail pave, has a V-cutout in the base, making the diamonds visible from the sides and allowing more light to hit diamonds. The diamonds are placed in such a way that very few or negligible metal shows on the ring. </span></p>
<br>
<p><b>U-Cut Pave</b></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">It is one of the most famous pave settings. The U-cut pave name comes from its shape as the diamonds are set in U shape. It looks unique and classy in appearance. U-cut pave's most amazing benefit is that it reduces the amount of metal and increases the diamond ratio. In U-cut pave, diamond sparkles from all angles. </span></p>
<br>
<p><b>Bright Cut Pave</b></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">Bright Cut Pave also called the Channel set pave, and it is the most traditional pave style. Bright cut pave holds diamond between two metal walls with a small prong to keep it in position. This paves setting's significant benefit is that it provides additional durability and keeps the diamond safe in metal walls. In comparison with other pave styles, it has a high metal ratio. </span></p>
<br>
<p><b>Scalloped Pave</b></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">Scalloped is one of the most unique and beautiful designs, and it attracts attention from its beautiful detailing. Scalloped pave metal beads cut into U shaped, and creates a scalloped pave. Scalloped paves are elegant and classy looking </span><b>pave diamond engagement rings</b><span style="font-weight: 400;">. There are many unique varieties within a scalloped pave, and designers can add their designs and styles to make it more beautiful and unique. But the concept is generally the same for the scalloped pave.</span></p>
<br>
<p><b>Petite Pave</b></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">Petite pave diamond settings are often confused with the micro-diamond setting. But Petite pave setting is focused on tiny prongs rather than small diamonds. In this type of setting, the diamond is more visible, giving it a spectacular look.</span></p>
<br>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">Now you know the different styles of Pave diamond engagement rings. Select the one which suits you according to your budget, maintenance, and style and surprise your partner with it!</span></p>]]>
    </content>
  </entry>
</feed>
